<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Authors | ADAL</title>
    <link>https://bluejayadal.github.io/authors/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://bluejayadal.github.io/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Authors</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© ADAL 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 09:32:15 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://bluejayadal.github.io/images/icon_hu67d8132adf6916bc3e83a7d6cad86df0_8135_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Authors</title>
      <link>https://bluejayadal.github.io/authors/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://bluejayadal.github.io/authors/admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 09:32:15 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bluejayadal.github.io/authors/admin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the Advanced Data Analytics Lab (ADAL) at Elizabethtown College. Our research focuses on two broad areas: (i) &lt;strong&gt;data analytics&lt;/strong&gt;: the delivery of new knowledge from enormous data with statistical modeling and machine learning, and (ii) &lt;strong&gt;distributed systems&lt;/strong&gt;: the development of distribute computing, networking and storage frameworks such as big data frameworks and blockchain systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Principal Investigator, Peilong Li, Ph.D., is an assistant professor of the Department of Computer Science at Elizabethtown College. He also oversees the Data Science Major in the department. He has received national and international wide recognition for his research and service contributions. For more details, visit his personal &lt;a href=&#34;https://peilong.github.io/&#34;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-to-expect-from-adal&#34;&gt;What to expect from ADAL&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Awaken your enthusiasm in data science&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete a data science project as an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.etown.edu/offices/registration-records/sle-list.aspx&#34;&gt;Signature Learning Experience (SLE)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work as a student researcher during summer and regular semesters (&lt;a href=&#34;post/join-us/&#34;&gt;how&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pursue your career as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://trends.google.com/trends/explore?cat=958&amp;amp;date=2010-02-03%202020-03-03&amp;amp;geo=US&amp;amp;q=data%20scientist&#34;&gt;data scientist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://bluejayadal.github.io/authors/derek-manning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 22:48:13 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bluejayadal.github.io/authors/derek-manning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;latest-news&#34;&gt;Latest News&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accepted by the Computer Science Ph.D. program at University of Wisconsin Madison with full tuition waiver and stipends, Fall 2020&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First-authored a paper with Dr. Peilong Li to be published by &lt;a href=&#34;https://icc2020.ieee-icc.org/&#34;&gt;IEEE International Conference on Communications&lt;/a&gt;, 7-11 June 2020&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2x Google Cloud First Team Academic All-America® (Baseball - 2018, 2019)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nathaniel Hager Jr Memorial Scholar	(2016, 2017, 2018)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recognized for academic achievement within the engineering department&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clark Associates, Inc. $5000 Leadership and Entrepreneurship Scholarship (2017)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emergent Scholar (2017)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Achieving cumulative GPA higher than 3.75 after first three semesters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;quotes-from-derek&#34;&gt;Quotes from Derek&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The summer I spent working in the ADAL lab was by far the most impactful experience I had at Elizabethtown. Working closely with Dr. Li, I was able to progress from having zero experience in an applied research area, to developing the skills to have a significant impact as a member of the research team. The 10-week experience provided me with the foundation to apply and gain admittance to the highly competitive PhD program of the University of Wisconsin Computer Science department, which is one of the fastest growing CS departments in the country. When visiting the campus to meet with professors, I pulled heavily from my summer research experience during the conversations to make a strong first impression on the faculty.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Even though I was also an athlete, I was still able to take part in the research opportunity. I think in general athletes that are also very good students may be hesitant in engaging in such activities because they think they will not have enough time to engage in training and also full time research, which I found was definitely not true at Etown.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://bluejayadal.github.io/authors/peilong-li/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 22:48:13 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bluejayadal.github.io/authors/peilong-li/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Peilong Li is an Assistant Professor at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.etown.edu/&#34;&gt;Elizabethtown College&lt;/a&gt;. He is oversees the Data Science Major and runs the &lt;a href=&#34;https://bluejayadal.github.io/&#34;&gt;Advanced Data Analytics Lab (ADAL)&lt;/a&gt; at the college. Prior to joining Etown, Dr. Li was a Research Assistant Professor at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uml.edu/&#34;&gt;University of Massachusetts Lowell&lt;/a&gt;. His research interests include Machine Learning, Software Defined Infrastructure, Big Data Analytics, and Parallel Computing and Computer Architecture. He has received three research grants from funding agencies including National Science Foundation and Intel Corporation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tong Zhang</title>
      <link>https://bluejayadal.github.io/authors/tong-zhang/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 22:48:13 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bluejayadal.github.io/authors/tong-zhang/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weigang Li</title>
      <link>https://bluejayadal.github.io/authors/weigang-li/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 22:48:13 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bluejayadal.github.io/authors/weigang-li/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xiaoban Wu</title>
      <link>https://bluejayadal.github.io/authors/xiaoban-wu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 22:48:13 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bluejayadal.github.io/authors/xiaoban-wu/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yan Luo</title>
      <link>https://bluejayadal.github.io/authors/yan-luo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 22:48:13 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bluejayadal.github.io/authors/yan-luo/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://bluejayadal.github.io/authors/christoph-schartner/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bluejayadal.github.io/authors/christoph-schartner/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://bluejayadal.github.io/authors/clay-buxton/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bluejayadal.github.io/authors/clay-buxton/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://bluejayadal.github.io/authors/connor-dileo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bluejayadal.github.io/authors/connor-dileo/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://bluejayadal.github.io/authors/jonathan-wiseman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bluejayadal.github.io/authors/jonathan-wiseman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;latest-news&#34;&gt;Latest News&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Started work at Elsevier, Inc. as a Software Engineer, June 2020&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Honors Thesis Grand Prize for “Monitoring Public Sentiment of NFL Draft Picks via Machine Learning Techniques,” Supervised by Dr. Li, May 2020&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graduated Summa Cum Laude from Elizabethtown College with Computer Science Honors, May 2020&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Completed Elizabethtown College Honors Program, May 2020&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;quotes-from-jonathan&#34;&gt;Quotes from Jonathan&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Through courses taught by Dr. Li, I was exposed to the field of Data Science for the first time.  I always had an interest in data and statistics but had never been able to find a creative application for them.  Through my courses I was able to gain some very strong foundational knowledge that I have used to explore subjects that are very interesting to me.  From sports like football to the applications of language analysis on large datasets, I have discovered new ways of applying the techniques of Data Science to produce meaningful observations about the world.  Dr. Li’s supervision of my thesis ultimately led to my winning of the Honors Program’s Grand Prize for Best Honors Thesis.  Overall, I owe a lot to both the knowledge and opportunities that the Computer Science department, and especially Dr. Li, have provided me with.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://bluejayadal.github.io/authors/kevin-carman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bluejayadal.github.io/authors/kevin-carman/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://bluejayadal.github.io/authors/matthew-grohotolski/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bluejayadal.github.io/authors/matthew-grohotolski/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;latest-news&#34;&gt;Latest News&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Published a paper with Dr. Peilong Li at &lt;a href=&#34;http://cse.buet.ac.bd/nsyss2020/&#34;&gt;2020 7th International Conference on Networking, Systems and Security&lt;/a&gt;, Dec. 22-24, 2020.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;quotes-from-matthew&#34;&gt;Quotes from Matthew&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The time I spent working on ADAL challenged me to develop and deploy advanced machine learning algorithms for network detection. It also strengthened my coding teamwork abilties as I was assisted by Connor DiLeo when working on the project.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
