<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ADAL</title>
    <link>https://bluejayadal.github.io/authors/admin/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://bluejayadal.github.io/authors/admin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>ADAL</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© ADAL 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 09:32:15 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://bluejayadal.github.io/images/icon_hu67d8132adf6916bc3e83a7d6cad86df0_8135_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>ADAL</title>
      <link>https://bluejayadal.github.io/authors/admin/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>ADAL receives two 2020 SCARP Grants</title>
      <link>https://bluejayadal.github.io/post/2020-scarp-grant/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 09:32:15 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bluejayadal.github.io/post/2020-scarp-grant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-1&#34;&gt;Project 1:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Performance Study between Machine Learning and Deep Learning Methods on Network Traffic Analysis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;principal-investigator-faculty-mentor&#34;&gt;Principal Investigator, Faculty Mentor:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Peilong Li&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;student-researchers&#34;&gt;Student Researchers:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthew Grohotolski, Connor DiLeo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;grant-amount&#34;&gt;Grant Amount:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$10,240&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;project-duration&#34;&gt;Project Duration:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8 Weeks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Applying machine learning techniques is a promising direction to classify traffic categories and identify malicious flows in both encrypted and plain network traffic. However, it remains an open problem as there are many challenges in training datasets, feature engineering, machine learning models: (1) the datasets used in prior works are heterogeneous in size, traffic types, encryption schemes, which make it difficult to generalize the findings from these research works; (2) it is still a debate whether to infer using network flow features or raw packet bytes as input, both of which have demonstrated a degree of effectiveness; (3) it is interesting to explore the design space of machine learning models, from traditional machine learning approaches to more recent deep neural networks. We aim to investigate whether the models have different effectiveness for different objectives (e.g. traffic classification vs malware detection).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-2&#34;&gt;Project 2:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building a Secure Inter-institutional Data Sharing Platform with Blockchain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;principal-investigator-faculty-mentor-1&#34;&gt;Principal Investigator, Faculty Mentor:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Jingwen Wang&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;student-researchers-1&#34;&gt;Student Researchers:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grace Cuff, Jeffry Edmonds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;grant-amount-1&#34;&gt;Grant Amount:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$9,440&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;project-duration-1&#34;&gt;Project Duration:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8 Weeks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;abstract-1&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Existing cyberinfrastrucure for inter-institutional data sharing faces challenges. Firstly, traditional infrastructure is a closed environment in a single or multiple fixed location, and cannot be used efficiently to share data securely among multiple institutions. For example, the patient data collected at a medical school cannot be readily shared with data scientist collaborators from a nearby institution. IRB approval, verifiable encryption and secure storage are only a few of the many prerequisites. Secondly, even though cloud services can provide a unified resource for institutional collaboration, the latency, bandwidth and cost of cloud-based computing do not scale well with emerging needs. Real-world cloud has its latency in the order of hundreds of milliseconds and its bandwidth is significantly limited by the shared network pipe. The cost incurred through compute time and storage can easily exceed research budget. Thirdly, there is no available open-sourced online portals that provide a clean interface for requesting and authenticating data to be used inter-institutionally.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Li serves as a Co-Chair of NetAML Workshop 2020</title>
      <link>https://bluejayadal.github.io/post/2020-netaml-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 15:31:13 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bluejayadal.github.io/post/2020-netaml-workshop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;program-committee-member&#34;&gt;Program Committee Member&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Li was honored to be one of the three organizing committee co-chairs for the upcoming 1st Workshop on Network Traffic Analytics using Machine Learning (&lt;a href=&#34;https://netaml.github.io/&#34;&gt;NetAML&lt;/a&gt;), co-located with IJCAI 2020 in Yokohama, Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a PC Co-Chair, Dr. Li will be helping find paper reviewers, review the paper submissions, judge the competition, and manage the workshop website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;netaml-workshop&#34;&gt;NETAML Workshop&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NETAML 2020 workshop aims to provide a venue for the community to present and discuss the latest advances in traffic analysis, with an emphasis on novel machine learning based approaches. Given the expertise from IJCAI-PRICAI20 attendees, we see this an excellent opportunity for networking researchers to interact with ML/AI community to foster new knowledges and advance the state of art. We expect to have papers contributed by researchers and practitioners, as well as invited talks by distinguished experts. In particular, we will organize a competition (NetAML Competition, sponsored by Intel Corp., pending approvals) at IJCAI- PRICAI20 on machine learning based traffic analytics before the deadline of the workshop submission, and encourage participants of the competition to submit papers to and present their results at the NETAML workshop. We hope this workshop will catalyze the research and development of novel methods for network traffic analytics with rich datasets, vigorous discussions, new directions and fruitful collaborations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are you interested in joining BlueJay ADAL?</title>
      <link>https://bluejayadal.github.io/post/join-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 18:16:49 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bluejayadal.github.io/post/join-us/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are always interested in recruiting talented students to join our research group. We also welcome inter-department and industry collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;signature-learning-experience&#34;&gt;Signature Learning Experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Undergraduate students can pursue research experiences in ADAL as an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.etown.edu/offices/registration-records/sle-list.aspx&#34;&gt;Signature Learning Experience&lt;/a&gt; (i.e. senior project) that can be counted towards your graduation credits. Possible courses under our supervision are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EGR 401/402 Senior Project in Engineering I/II&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CS 400 Projects in Computing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CS 495 Honors Projects in Computing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DS 452 Data Science Capstone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summer-creative-arts-and-research-program&#34;&gt;Summer Creative Arts and Research Program&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another way of participation is through the Summer Creative Arts and Research Program (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.etown.edu/offices/research/summer-scholarship.aspx&#34;&gt;SCARP&lt;/a&gt;) from which you can get up to 10-week-long paid research work plus free meal and board on campus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We welcome applications from computer science, engineering, mathematics, chemistry, biology or other related majors. Applicants should have proficient programming experience in Python (understanding another OOP language such as Java and C++ is a plus), and be familiar with software development environments and tools in Linux. The ideal applicants should also have taken &lt;em&gt;DS200 Intro to Data Science&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;DS300 Data Mining&lt;/em&gt; offered by the Data Science Major at Etown College. The student researchers will be expected to work effectively both independently and in a team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-opportunities&#34;&gt;Other Opportunities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Projects funded by external funding agencies are available from time to time. Students could potentially work as research assistants during regular semesters, however the screening process is very strict in this category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the undergraduate research opportunities in our laboratory, please direct your message to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:lip@etown.edu&#34;&gt;Dr. Li&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper Accepted by IEEE International Conference on Communications 2020</title>
      <link>https://bluejayadal.github.io/post/2019-icc-aceta/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 15:47:50 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bluejayadal.github.io/post/2019-icc-aceta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;aceta-paper-accepted&#34;&gt;ACETA Paper Accepted&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our paper entitled &amp;ldquo;ACETA: Accelerating Encrypted Traffic Analytics on Network Edge&amp;rdquo; was accepted to be appearing in proceedings of IEEE International Conference on Communications 2020. The average IEEE ICC paper acceptance rate is 38%. Congratulations to Derek Manning and the team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ADAL receives a 2019 SCARP Grant</title>
      <link>https://bluejayadal.github.io/post/2019-scarp-grant/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 11:32:06 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bluejayadal.github.io/post/2019-scarp-grant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-name&#34;&gt;Project Name:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Machine Learning Based Encrypted Network Traffic Analysis on Multicore Processors&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;principal-investigator-faculty-mentor&#34;&gt;Principal Investigator, Faculty Mentor:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Peilong Li&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;student-researchers&#34;&gt;Student Researchers:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Derek Manning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;grant-amount&#34;&gt;Grant Amount:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$6,200&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;project-duration&#34;&gt;Project Duration:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10 Weeks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Applying machine learning techniques to detect malicious encrypted network traffic has become a challenging research topic since traditional approaches based on studying network patterns fail to operate on encrypted data, especially without compromising the integrity of encryption. Traditional solutions to identify network threats fall into two major categories: 1) deep packet inspection and signatures; and 2) offline network pattern training. However, the first category is not applicable on encrypted traffic. Furthermore, solutions that work on decrypted network data will expose the privacy of the network users, and are computationally intensive. By passively monitoring malicious behaviors on a session-based level, the second category of traditional solutions demonstrate high accuracy and low false positives. However, extracting network data features and applying machine learning based classifiers “in-flight” are challenging due to the high computational power and low response latency requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
